Register of the Kyril Drenikoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1879-1983 (Boxes 75-145)
  - Concert tours
    - Italy
      See Concert tours - Bulgaria
  - Confederación Anticomunista Latinoamericana, 1975-1982 (Folder 104: 4)
  - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe, 1972-1973 (Folder 104: 5)
    Includes material on Baltic countries
  - Confidentiel (Folder 104: 6)
  - Conservation of Natural Resources, 1979 (Folder 104: 7)
  - Council Against Communist Aggression, 1974-1976 (Folder 104: 8)
  - Council on American Affairs, 1975 (Folder 104: 9)
  - Cristofv, Cristjo (Folder 104: 10)
    Includes his correspondence and writings
  - Croatian Liberation Movement, 1983 (Folder 104: 11)
  - Croatian Liberation Movement, 1983 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Cuba, 1970-1978 (Folder 105: 2-3)
  - Cyprus (Folder 105: 4)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 105: 5)
  - Dellin, L. A. D., 1960-1977 (Folder 105: 6)
  - Demokraticheskata partiia (Bulgaria), 1899-1910 (Folder 105: 7)
  - Deutsch-Bulgarische Gesellschaft, 1937-1954 (Folder 105: 8)
  - Dimitrov, Georges, 1982 (Folder 105: 9)
  - Dimizkof, Konstantin St., 1954 (Folder 105: 10)
  - Dimov-Bogoev, Cristobal, 1960-1982 (Folder 105: 11)
  - Diplomats - Bulgaria (Folder 105: 12-13)
  - Divination (Box-folder 106: 1)
  - Dobrich, Lazar (Folder 106: 2)
  - Dobroudja (Romania and Bulgaria) - History (Folder 106: 3)
  - Druzhestvo "Todor Aleksandrov,", 1961-1976 (Folder 106: 4)
  - Druzhestvoto na bulgarskite pisateli I kulturni deitsi v izgnanie (Union of Bulgarian writers in exile), 1974-1979 (Folder 106: 5)
  - Druzhestvoto na Svobodnite Bulgari v Velikobritania, 1953 (Folder 106: 6)
  - Early, George H. (Folder 106: 7)
  - Education - Bulgaria (Folder 106: 8)
  - Education, Communist (Folder 106: 9-10)
  - Edward VII, King of Great Britain, 1841-1910. Program of funeral ceremonial, 1910 May 20 (Folder 106: 11)
  - Eichman, Adolf, 1961 (Folder 106: 12)
  - Elections - Bulgaria (Folder 106: 13)
  - Electrification - Bulgaria, 1956-1971 (Folder 106: 14)
  - Electronica (Folder 106: 15)
  - Elisayeff, Boris, 1980 (Folder 106: 16)
  - Euro-African Foundation, 1972-1979 (Folder 106: 17)
  - Euroitalia (Agenzia Quotidiana di Informazione per la Stampa), 1978-1979 (Folder 106: 18)
  - European Community of Journalists, 1962-1983 (Folder 106: 19)
  - European Community of Journalists, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 107: 1)
  - European Conference for Human Rights and Selfdetermination, 1974 (Folder 107: 2)
  - European countries (Folder 107: 3-6)
  - European countries (Box-folder 108: 1-3)
  - European countries (Box-folder 109: 1-2)
  - European Federation Overseas Repatriates and East-European Refugee Organizations, 1979-1983 (Folder 109: 3)
  - European Freedom Council, 1971 (Folder 109: 4)
  - European Parliament Assembly (Folder 109: 5)
  - European Union, 1978-1983 (Folder 109: 6)
  - Fédération Internationale des Droits de l'Homme, 1978 (Folder 109: 7-8)
  - Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, 1861-1948
    - Appeals
      - To support Russia against Germany and Austria (Folder 109: 9)
      - To the People's Representatives (Folder 109: 10)
    - Coat of arms (Folder 109: 11)
    - Correspondence,, including with Todor Aleksandroff, Andrei Liapcheff, Mikhail Miroff, Vikenti Peev, D. Petkoff, Jiovanni Romanoff, M. Stoiloff, Damien Theelen, and Cosima Wagner, 1894-1942 (Folder 109: 12-26)
    - Medical report, 1943 August 26 (Box-folder 110: 1)
    - Order #1705, Sofiisko Gradsko-Obshchestvenno Upravlenie, 1914 September 30 (Folder 110: 2)
    - Proclamation, 1900 March 21 (Folder 110: 3)
    - Program for celebration of 28th birthday,, Plovdiv, Bulgaria, 1889 February 14 (Folder 110: 4)
    - Sentence of the State Court regarding former cabinet ministers, Sofia, 1903 (Folder 110: 5)
    - Water color paintings (Folder 110: 6)
  - Figueiredo, Carlos de Newton (Folder 110: 7)
  - Finance - Bulgaria (Folder 110: 8)
  - Folk art - Bulgaria (Folder 110: 9)
    See Bulgaria/Civilization
  - Fondation Convergence Occidentale, Lisbon, 1973-1974 (Folder 110: 10)
  - Fondation de la Confédération Mondiale des Anciens Elèves des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes, 1959-1961 (Folder 110: 11)
  - Fondazione Europea Dragan, 1969-1976 (Folder 110: 12)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)
    - General, 1970-1975 (Folder 110: 13)
    - General, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 111: 1-4)
    - General, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 112: 1)
    - Coin Plan, 1968-1970 (Folder 112: 2)
      Includes information on Yemen
  - Formentini, Antonio, 1961-1970 (Folder 112: 3)
    Includes correspondence
  - Foundation of the Mexican Anticommunist Federation, 1972 (Folder 112: 4)
  - France
    - General (Folder 112: 5-6)
    - History (Folder 112: 7-8)
  - Free Europe Committee, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 113: 1-2)
  - Frente Unido Nacionalista (Folder 113: 3)
  - Gabenski, Ivanko (Folder 113: 4-7)
    Includes material on the Bulgarian economy and on Italo-Bulgarian commercial relations
  - Gagov, Joseph M. (Folder 113: 8-9)
    See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Gagov, Joseph M.
  - Gagov, Joseph M. (Box-folder 114: 1)
  - Gal, Albert (Folder 114: 2)
  - Garcia, Marianella, 1983 (Folder 114: 3)
  - Gemedjisky-Rosniansky, Emilia (Folder 114: 4)
  - Genocide (Folder 114: 5)
  - Georgiev, Asen, 1963-1964 (Folder 114: 6)
  - Georgiev, Boris (Folder 114: 7-8)
  - Gerchev, Stephan (Folder 114: 9)
  - German-Bulgarian Association, 1954-1961 (Folder 114: 10)
  - Germany (Folder 114: 11)
  - Germany. Geheime Staatspolizei (Folder 114: 12)
  - Gorski, Dragan, 1970-1976 (Folder 114: 13)
  - Le Grand Livre du Mois, 1983 (Folder 114: 14)
  - Grazia, Guido, 1952-1975 (Folder 114: 15-16)
  - Great Britain (Folder 114: 17)
  - Greece (Folder 114: 18)
  - Greece (Box-folder 115: 1)
  - Grigorenko, General (Folder 115: 2)
  - Groueff, Stéphane (Folder 115: 3)
  - Hecate (Folder 115: 4)
  - History, Modern, 1925 (Folder 115: 5-6)
  - Human rights
    - China (Folder 115: 7)
      See also: Amitiés Belgo-Chinoises
      Includes petition signed by Kyril Drenikoff and others addressed to the President of South Korea, undated, relating to Chinese citizens.
    - Communist countries (Folder 115: 8)
  - Hungary, 1943 (Folder 115: 9)
  - Institut d'Etudes Balkaniques (Folder 115: 10)
  - Institut d'Etudes Slaves, 1969-1974 (Folder 115: 11)
  - Institut Economique de Paris, 1983 (Folder 115: 12)
  - International Business Machines of Belgium (IBM), 1983 (Folder 115: 13)
  - International Commission of Jurists, 1982 (Folder 115: 14)
  - International Committee for Unity and Universality of Culture, 1959 (Folder 115: 15)
  - International Conference to Win the Cold War, 1974 (Folder 115: 16)
  - International Federation for Victory over Communism, 1971-1972 (Folder 115: 17)
  - International law (Folder 115: 18-19)
  - International law (Box-folder 116: 1-3)
  - International League for Human Rights, 1973-1978 (Folder 116: 4)
    Includes lists of members from Bulgaria
  - International Press Agency, 1969 (Folder 116: 5)
  - International Refugee Organization (Italy), 1949 (Folder 116: 6)
    Includes certificates of people who received help
  - International relations and culture (Folder 116: 7)
  - Italy
    - General (Folder 116: 8-9)
    - General (Box-folder 117: 1)
    - Economic conditions
      See Gabenski, Ivanko
  - Iurikov, Vasil (Folder 117: 2)
  - Ivanov, T. (Folder 117: 3)
  - Javacheff, Christo (Folder 117: 4)
  - Jews (Folder 117: 5-12)
  - Joanna, queen consort of Boris, Czar of Bulgaria (Box-folder 118: 1)
    See also: BORIS III, CZAR OF BULGARIA FILE/Subject file
  - Jurisprudence
    - General (Folder 118: 2)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 118: 3-6)
    - Bulgaria (Box-folder 119: 1-5)
    - France (Folder 119: 6-8)
    - France (Box-folder 120: 1-5)
    - France (Box-folder 121: 1-2)
    - Germany (Folder 121: 3)
    - Italy (Folder 121: 4)
  - Kabinet na Demokraticheskoto Edinstvo (Bulgaria) (Folder 121: 5)
  - Katzarov, Konstantin, 1965-1980 (Folder 121: 6)
  - Kernicheva, Mencha (Folder 121: 7)
  - Khmer Friendship Committee (Folder 121: 8-9)
  - Kiukov, Luben
    - General, 1967-1972 (Folder 121: 10)
    - L'homme de Tchéliabinsk (translated into French by Kyril Drenikoff under the pseudonym of K. D. Gueorguief), ca. 1972
      - Typescript, undated (Folder 121: 11)
      - Correspondence with or of Kyril Drenikoff, Dimco Stateff, Editions Denoël, and Marcel Legrand, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 122: 1)
        Includes contracts
      - Publicity material, 1972 (Folder 122: 2)
  - Komitet "Bulgaria nad Vsichko,", 1973 (Folder 122: 3)
  - Komitet "Deviatii Avgust." Appeal to the Bulgarian Army (Folder 122: 4)
  - Korea (South)
  - Korea Security Parachute Cooperation Limited (KSPC Limited), 1982 (Folder 122: 5)
  - Kristeva, Julia (Folder 122: 6)
  - Kurteff, Cirillo, 1971-1983 (Folder 122: 7)
  - Kurteff, Kristo, 1979 (Folder 122: 8)
  - Kyril, Archbishop (Folder 122: 9)
  - Labin, Suzanne (Folder 122: 10)
  - Latvian Welfare Fund, 1973 (Folder 122: 11)
  - League of Nations, 1922 (Folder 122: 12)
  - Legal services - Bulgaria, 1899-1902 (Folder 122: 13)
  - Legislation - Europe, 1958 (Folder 122: 14)
  - Levski, Vasil (Folder 122: 15)
  - Liberalna partiia (Bulgaria), 1902 (Folder 122: 16)
  - Lithuania, 1973 (Folder 122: 17-18)
  - Lukov, Khristo, 1943 (Folder 122: 19)
  - Lulchev, Nikolai, 1977 (Folder 122: 20)
  - Lutheran theology and the Catholic Church, 1983 (Folder 122: 21)
  - Macedonia
    - General (Folder 123: 1-8)
    - General (Box-folder 124: 1)
    - Appeal to Macedonians for an independent Bulgaria, 1901 November 17 (Folder 124: 2)
    - Miscellany (Folder 124: 3)
  - Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States and Canada
    - General (Folder 124: 4-6)
    - Youth Section (YMPO) (Folder 124: 7)
  - Magic (Folder 124: 8)
  - Makedono-Odrinski Komitet, Sofia, 1901-1902 (Folder 124: 9)
  - Makedonski Natsionalen Komitet, 1928 (Folder 124: 10)
  - Maleev, Luka, 1953 (Folder 124: 11)
  - Marinoff, Slavi, 1967 (Folder 124: 12)
  - Markoff, Georgi, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - Matheeff, Mitko (Folder 125: 2)
  - Medals (Folder 125: 3-7)
  - Medals (Box-folder 126: 1-2)
  - Medicine - Bulgaria (Folder 126: 3)
  - Mikhailov, Ivan, 1963-1974 (Folder 126: 4)
  - Mikhailov, Vasil (Folder 126: 5)
  - Mission "Your Neighbour in Need," Bulgaria, 1982 (Folder 126: 6)
  - Monarchy (Folder 126: 7-8)
  - Monarchy (Box-folder 127: 1-8)
  - Moor, Jean-Baptiste van (Folder 128: 1)
  - Moroz, Valentin, 1979 (Folder 128: 2)
  - Mouvement d'Action pour l'Union Européenne, 1981-1982 (Folder 128: 3)
  - Mouvement de Libération Bulgare (Folder 128: 4)
  - Mouvement pour la Libération de la Croatie en Belgique, 1972-1982 (Folder 128: 5)
  - Movimiento de Liberación Nacional, Guatemala, 1976 (Folder 128: 6)
  - Movimiento Democratico Nicaraguense, San José, Costa Rica, 1983 (Folder 128: 7)
  - Mücke, Hellmuth von (Folder 128: 8)
    Includes correspondence of Zlatka Kermektchieff with Karl Dönitz and others
  - Murder victims - Bulgaria (Folder 128: 9)
    Includes list of concentration camps in Bulgaria
  - Nakov, Andrei. Material relating to Russian art, 1972-1982 (Folder 128: 10)
  - National Committee of the Union of Macedonian Emigrant Associations in Bulgaria, 1928 (Folder 128: 11)
  - National Palace Museum, Taipei, Taiwan, 1979 (Folder 128: 12)
  - Natsionalni Bulgarski politicheski emigrantski organizatsii, 1953-1959 (Folder 128: 13)
  - Natural resources - Bulgaria (Folder 128: 14)
  - Navachine, Dimitri (Folder 128: 15)
  - Newspapers - Europe (Folder 128: 16)
  - Nikolaev, N. P., 1958 (Folder 128: 17)
  - Nikoloff, Stoyan, 1951-1969 (Folder 128: 18)
  - North America (Folder 128: 19)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1972 (Folder 128: 20)
  - North Korea, 1978 (Box-folder 129: 1)
  - Numismatics - Bulgaria (Folder 129: 2-5)
  - XI Obyknivenno Narodno Sobranie, 1901 (Folder 129: 6)
  - Obituaries
    - General, 1962-1976 (Folder 129: 7)
    - Bulgarians
      - Died in Bulgaria, 1964-1983 (Folder 129: 8)
      - Died in exile, 1944-1980 (Folder 129: 9)
  - Obshchobulgarski Soiuz za Natsionalno Spasenie, 1972 (Folder 129: 10)
  - Omega
    - 1965 (Folder 130: 1)
    - 1970-1972 (Folder 130: 2)
  - Ordre du Rouvre, 1972 (Folder 130: 3)
  - Ordre Souverain et Militaire du Temple de Jérusalem (Folder 130: 4)
  - Organisation Armée Secrète, 1967 (Folder 130: 5)
  - Organizatsia "Svobodnite Bulgari," Paris, 1949-1952 (Folder 130: 6)
  - Orthodox churches in the free world, 1964-1978 (Folder 130: 7-9)
  - Padev, Michael, 1963 (Folder 130: 10)
  - Painting - Turkey, 1911 (Folder 130: 11)
  - Paneff, Dimiter (Folder 130: 12)
  - Papen, Franz von, 1969 (Folder 130: 13)
  - Peace movements (Folder 130: 14)
  - Peikov, Assen, 1945-1979 (Folder 130: 15-16)
  - Peikov, Ilia (Box-folder 131: 1-3)
  - Peltekoff, P.
  - Petercheff, Richard, 1979 (Folder 131: 4)
  - Petroff, Mitko (Folder 131: 5)
  - Philosophy, Marxist, 1974-1978 (Folder 131: 6)
  - The Plain-Speaker: The Organ of Integralism, 1965 (Folder 131: 7)
  - Poetry (Folder 131: 8-9)
  - Poetry (Box-folder 132: 1-7)
  - Poland (Folder 133: 1)
  - Political humor
    - General (Folder 133: 2)
    - "Zad zheleznata zavesa,", 1957 (Folder 133: 3)
  - Political persecution - Bulgaria, 1974 (Folder 133: 4)
  - Pondeva, Raina, 1978 (Folder 133: 5)
  - Popowa, S. D., 1926 (Folder 133: 6)
  - Portugal (Folder 133: 7)
  - Posnova, Irène, 1961-1967 (Folder 133: 8)
  - Pythagoras (Folder 133: 9)
  - Quénard, Gervasio P., 1961 (Folder 133: 10)
  - Rabotnicheska Sotsialdemokraticheska Partiia (Bulgaria), 1902-1914 (Folder 133: 11)
  - Radio Free Europe
    - Broadcasts, 1963-1964 (Folder 133: 12-13)
    - Bulgarian Press Survey, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - Radio Maritza, 1952 (Folder 134: 2)
  - Radio Sofia, 1964 (Folder 134: 3)
  - Radio Vaticana, 1962-1977 (Folder 134: 4)
  - Radomir, Duke
    See Russia - History - Alexander III
  - Ragno, Gino (Folder 134: 5)
  - Reagan, Ronald - Proclamation on the Hungarian Freedom Fighter's Day, 1981 October 23 (Folder 134: 6)
  - Refugees - Bulgaria
    See Bulgarskia Komitet za Podpomagane na Bezhantsite Bulgari Namitashchi se v Italia, Gertsia i Turtsia; Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari, Rome; Travailleurs Réfugiés Bulgares en Belgique
  - Religion and politics (Folder 134: 7)
  - Rencontres Internationales (Folder 134: 8)
  - Romania (Folder 134: 9-10)
  - Russia - History - Alexander III, 1881-1894. Certificate signed by Tsar Alexander honoring Duke Radomir of Bulgaria, 1881 August (Folder 134: 11)
  - Saint-Pierre, Michel (Folder 134: 12)
  - Sakharov International Committee (Folder 134: 13)
  - Salvini, Luigi (Folder 134: 14)
  - Savov, Sava, 1928 (Folder 134: 15)
  - Scandinavia (Folder 134: 16)
  - Schischkoff, Georgi, 1958-1977 (Folder 134: 17)
  - Schischkoff, Stephen, 1967 (Box-folder 135: 1)
  - Schiwkowa, Ljudmila, 1981 (Folder 135: 2)
  - Sculpture - Bulgaria (Folder 135: 3)
  - Silianoff, Eugène (Folder 135: 4)
  - Skopska Akademia (Folder 135: 5)
  - Slavianski Komitet v Bulgaria, 1973-1982 (Folder 135: 6)
  - Slipyi, Joseph, 1963-1981 (Folder 135: 7)
  - Slovo, 1974 April (Folder 135: 8)
  - Social sciences - Experiments, Rome, 1963 (Folder 135: 9)
  - Socialist block (Folder 135: 10-11)
  - Socialist block (Box-folder 136: 1-2)
  - Socialist Labour Party, 1945 (Folder 136: 3)
  - Sociedade de Estudos Politicos Economicos e Sociales, 1975-1976 (Folder 136: 4)
  - Società Italiana per l'Organizzazione Internazionale, 1965 (Folder 136: 5)
  - Società Italo-Bulgara (Folder 136: 6)
    Account of an exhibit in Italy of Bulgarian graphic artists
  - Société Bulgare de Bienfaisance à Bucarest (Folder 136: 7)
  - Société Sofia, Paris, 1973 (Folder 136: 8)
  - Sofia State University Library (Folder 136: 9)
  - Soiuz na Bulgarskite Pisateli (Folder 136: 10)
  - Soiuz na Bulgarskite Revoliutsionni Komitet, 1978-1979 (Folder 136: 11)
  - Sokatscheff, Narziss, 1981 (Folder 136: 12)
  - South America (Folder 136: 13-14)
  - Soviet Union
    - General, 1956-1982 (Folder 136: 15-16)
    - General, 1956-1982 (Box-folder 137: 1-3)
    - History - Revolution, 1917-1921 (Folder 137: 4)
    - Politics and government, 1967-1969 (Folder 137: 5)
    - Social conditions (Folder 137: 6)
      Memoir of unidentified author
  - Spain (Box-folder 138: 1-3)
  - Spanish National Radio, Bulgarian section, 1969-1963 (Folder 138: 4-5)
  - Sports - Bulgaria (Folder 138: 6-7)
  - Stainov, Petko, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 139: 1)
  - Stamp collecting
    - Biafra
      See CORRESPONDENCE/Azikiwe, N. and Dimitroff, Ivan (relates to the printing and issuance of Biafran stamps to benefit Biafran children)
    - Bulgaria, 1983 (Folder 139: 2)
  - Stanchov, Dimiter (Folder 139: 3)
  - Stateff, Christo, 1950-1967 (Folder 139: 4)
  - Stelios M. Stelson Foundation, Inc., 1975 (Folder 139: 5)
  - Stetzko, Yaroslav (Folder 139: 6)
    See also: ANTI-BOLSHEVIK BLOCK OF NATIONS (ABN)
  - Stig, Chanel (Folder 139: 7)
  - Südosteuropa-Gesellschaft, Munich, 1964 (Folder 139: 8)
  - Svirdlev, Stefan (Folder 139: 9)
  - Swedish Freedom Council, 1973 (Folder 139: 10)
  - Syndicat des Journalistes et Ecrivains, 1968 (Folder 139: 11)
  - Tainyi Ofitserski Soiuz (Folder 139: 12)
  - Taiwan, Sheng yi hui (Taiwan Provincial Assembly, Wufeng, Taichung, Taiwan), 1983 (Folder 139: 13)
  - Talbieh Psychiatric Hospital, Jerusalem, 1966 (Folder 139: 14)
  - Talmud - Criticism, interpretation, etc. (Folder 139: 15)
  - Tarnovalisky, Andrei, 1974-1976 (Folder 139: 16)
  - Tecos (Mexico) (secret society) (Folder 139: 17)
  - Témoignages: Revue de documentation sur l'Europe centrale et orientale, Monaco, 1968 (Folder 139: 18)
  - Tenev, S., 1921-1922 (Folder 139: 19)
  - Terrorism - Bulgaria (Folder 139: 20)
  - Tilapia Food Aid Organization, 1983 (Folder 139: 21)
  - Tourism - Bulgaria (Folder 139: 22)
  - Tourism - Bulgaria (Folder 140: 1-2)
  - Transylvania (Folder 140: 3)
  - Travailleurs Réfugiés Bulgares en Belgique (Folder 140: 4)
  - Trepkov, T. (Folder 140: 5)
  - Turkey (Folder 140: 6-7)
  - Ukraine (Folder 140: 8-12)
  - Ukraine (Box-folder 141: 1-3)
  - Unione Monarchica Italiana, 1977-1978 (Folder 141: 4)
  - United Nations
    - General (Folder 141: 5-6)
    - Declaration, 1948 December 10 (Folder 141: 7)
    - Report of the United Nations Special Committee on the Balkans, New York, 1949 (Folder 141: 8)
  - United States
    - General (Folder 141: 9)
    - Politics and government, 1972-1973 (Folder 141: 10-12)
  - United States Information Service, 1964 (Folder 141: 13)
  - Vankerkhoven, Paul (Box-folder 142: 1-3)
  - Vartan, Silvie, 1972 (Folder 142: 4)
  - Vatican (Folder 142: 5)
  - Velizarov, Bogdan P., 1969 (Folder 142: 6)
  - Vietnam, 1974 (Folder 142: 7)
  - Visits of State - Bulgaria (Folder 142: 8)
  - Visits of State - Bulgaria (Box-folder 143: 1-2)
  - Volkov, Ivan, 1930-1931 (Folder 143: 3)
  - Vsebulgarski Soiuz "Otets Paisii," Sofia, 1930 (Folder 143: 4)
  - Walsh, Patrick (Folder 143: 5)
  - West Germany (Folder 143: 6)
  - World Christian Congress (9th) and World Chinese Christian Conference (10th),, Taipei, Taiwan, China, 1981 (Folder 143: 7)
  - World Congress of Former Students of de la Salle Brothers
    - 1st Congress, Brussels, Belgium, 1958 October (Folder 143: 8)
    - 2nd Congress, Rome, Italy, 1960 September (Folder 143: 9)
    - 3rd Congress, Barcelona, Spain, 1964 September (Folder 143: 10)
    - 3rd Congress, Barcelona, Spain, 1964 September (Box-folder 144: 1)
    - 4th Congress, Québec, Canada, 1967 August (Folder 144: 2)
  - World politics - 20th century (Folder 144: 3)
  - World War, 1914-1918 (Folder 144: 4-6)
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - Battlefields - Balkans (Folder 144: 7)
    - Secret service
      - Bulgaria (Folder 144: 8)
      - Soviet Union
        See SUBJECT FILE/World War, 1939-1945 - Secret service/Bulgaria
  - Yemen
    See Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)
  - Yordanov, Dimitri (Folder 144: 9)
  - Youth - Bulgaria, 1967-1968 (Folder 144: 10)
  - Youth - Bulgaria, 1967-1968 (Folder 145: 1-3)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 145: 4-5)
  - Zagoroff, Slavtcho (Folder 145: 6)
  - Zarev, Christian, 1971 (Folder 145: 7)
  - Zlatareff, Ilia (Folder 145: 8)
  - Zoltschew, Theodor D., 1968-1981 (Folder 145: 9)
  - Miscellany (Folder 145: 10)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1886-1983 (Boxes 146-199)
  Clippings, magazines, monographs, newspapers, and pamphlets and serials, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: OVERSIZE FILE/Printed matter.
  - Clippings (Boxes 146-176)
  - Magazines (Boxes 177-181)
  - Monographs (Boxes 182-184)
  - Newspapers (Boxes 185-186)
  - Pamphlets and serials (Boxes 187-199)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1849-1983 (Boxes 200-214)
  Address, agreements and treaties, appeals, birthday greeting, bonds, bookplates, calendars, caricatures, certificates and diplomas (including of Georgi and Kyril Drenikoff), computer portrait, guest book, itinerary, magazines and newspapers, manifesto, passport, petition, program, statutes, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Address to their majesties Simeon II, King of Bulgaria, and Queen Margarita in memory of their visit to the Bulgarian colony in Chicago, 1966 February 28 (Folder 200: 1)
  - Agreements and treaties
    - General
      - With Germany (Folder 200: 2)
      - With Turkey (Folder 200: 3)
    - "Ratifications de Sa Majesté le Roi des Bulgares sur le traité de paix conclu le 27 novembre 1919 à Neuilly-sur-Seine entre la Bulgarie et les Etats-Unis d'Amérique, l'Empire Britannique, la France, l'Italie, le Japon, la Belgique, la Chine, le Cuba, la Grèce, le Hedjaz, la Pologne, le Portugal, la Roumanie, l'Etat Serbe-Croate-Slovène, le Siam et la Tchéco-Slovaquie" (Folder 200: 4)
  - Appeals
    - From M. A. Dumbalakov, undated (Folder 201: 1)
    - From the Bulgarian youth to General Ivan Volkov, undated (Folder 201: 2)
    - From the Macedonian Patriotic Organizations in the United States, Canada, Brazil, Austria and New Zealand, undated (Folder 201: 3)
    - From the people's representatives of Bulgaria, undated (Folder 201: 4)
    - From Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, 1896 February 4 (Folder 201: 5)
    - From the Ligue de Bienfaisance des Catholiques Macédoniens, 1925 (Folder 201: 6)
    - From the Bulgarian Liberation Movement to the Bulgarian people, 1969 (Folder 201: 7)
  - Birthday greeting to Kyril Drenikoff, 1978 July 30 (Folder 201: 8)
  - Bonds, Mexican, 1895 1904 (Folder 201: 9)
  - Bookplates (Folder 201: 10-11)
  - Calendars (Folder 201: 12-13)
  - Caricatures (Folder 201: 14)
  - Certificates and diplomas
    - General
      - To Victor Hugo from the Bulgarian Central Charity Society, 1876 October 26 (Folder 202: 1)
      - To Radomirskata Pesha Druzhina, from Alexander I, for participating in the campaign, 1877-1878 1881 August 30 (Folder 202: 2)
      - To Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, from the Palestinian Orthodox Society, 1884 January 16 (Folder 202: 3)
      - To Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, from the German Embassy in Vienna asking that civilian and military authorities allow him and his entourage to travel unhindered through France and Belgium, 1887 February 14 (Folder 202: 4)
      - To Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, the order "For Bravery,", 1887 October (Folder 202: 5)
      - To Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, from the Macedonian Central Revolutionary Committee, 1903 January 23 (Folder 202: 6)
      - To General Ivan Volkov, Bulgarian Minister of Defense, from the citizens of Kazanlok, 1925-1928 (Folder 202: 7-8)
      - To General Ivan Volkov, Bulgarian Minister of Defense, 1927 (Folder 202: 9)
      - To General Ivan Volkov, Bulgarian Minister of Defense from the veterans of the Balkan Wars and World War I, 1929 (Folder 202: 10)
      - To Ferdinand I, Czar of Bulgaria, from the National Geographic Society, Washington, D.C., 1935 January 23 (Folder 202: 11)